<TEI xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0">
   <teiHeader>
      <fileDesc>
         <titleStmt>
            <title>Of times and seasons, their mystery by the Lady Eleanor.</title>
            <author>Eleanor, Lady, d. 1652.</author>
         </titleStmt>
         <editionStmt>
            <edition>
               <date>1651</date>
            </edition>
         </editionStmt>
         <extent>Approx. 6 KB of XML-encoded text transcribed from 5 1-bit group-IV TIFF page images.</extent>
         <publicationStmt>
            <publisher>Text Creation Partnership,</publisher>
            <pubPlace>Ann Arbor, MI ; Oxford (UK) :</pubPlace>
            <date when="2014-11">2014-11 (EEBO-TCP Phase 2).</date>
            <idno type="DLPS">A36416</idno>
            <idno type="STC">Wing D2000</idno>
            <idno type="STC">ESTC R37756</idno>
            <idno type="EEBO-CITATION">17009977</idno>
            <idno type="OCLC">ocm 17009977</idno>
            <idno type="VID">105773</idno>
            <availability>
               <p>To the extent possible under law, the Text Creation Partnership has waived all copyright and related or neighboring rights to this keyboarded and encoded edition of the work described above, according to the terms of the CC0 1.0 Public Domain Dedication (http://creativecommons.org/publicdomain/zero/1.0/). This waiver does not extend to any page images or other supplementary files associated with this work, which may be protected by copyright or other license restrictions. Please go to https://www.textcreationpartnership.org/ for more information about the project.</p>
            </availability>
         </publicationStmt>
         <seriesStmt>
            <title>Early English books online text creation partnership.</title>
         </seriesStmt>
         <notesStmt>
            <note>(EEBO-TCP ; phase 2, no. A36416)</note>
            <note>Transcribed from: (Early English Books Online ; image set 105773)</note>
            <note>Images scanned from microfilm: (Early English books, 1641-1700 ; 1614:13)</note>
         </notesStmt>
         <sourceDesc>
            <biblFull>
               <titleStmt>
                  <title>Of times and seasons, their mystery by the Lady Eleanor.</title>
                  <author>Eleanor, Lady, d. 1652.</author>
               </titleStmt>
               <extent>8 p.   </extent>
               <publicationStmt>
                  <publisher>[s.n.],</publisher>
                  <pubPlace>[London] printed :</pubPlace>
                  <date>1651.</date>
               </publicationStmt>
               <notesStmt>
                  <note>"British Museum Catalogue gives [London] as place of publication"--NUC pre-1956 imprints.</note>
                  <note>Imperfect: lacks all after p. 8; best copy available for photographing. Bound and filmed with D1979 (The bill of excommunication) and D2004 (A prophesie of the last day) following.</note>
                  <note>Reproduction of original in the British Library.</note>
                  <note>With: The bill of excommunication / the Lady Eleanor. [London? : s.n], 1649 -- A prophesie of the last day / the Lady Eleanor. London printed : [s.n.], 1645.</note>
               </notesStmt>
            </biblFull>
         </sourceDesc>
      </fileDesc>
      <encodingDesc>
         <projectDesc>
            <p>Created by converting TCP files to TEI P5 using tcp2tei.xsl,
      TEI @ Oxford.
      </p>
         </projectDesc>
         <editorialDecl>
            <p>EEBO-TCP is a partnership between the Universities of Michigan and Oxford and the publisher ProQuest to create accurately transcribed and encoded texts based on the image sets published by ProQuest via their Early English Books Online (EEBO) database (http://eebo.chadwyck.com). The general aim of EEBO-TCP is to encode one copy (usually the first edition) of every monographic English-language title published between 1473 and 1700 available in EEBO.</p>
            <p>EEBO-TCP aimed to produce large quantities of textual data within the usual project restraints of time and funding, and therefore chose to create diplomatic transcriptions (as opposed to critical editions) with light-touch, mainly structural encoding based on the Text Encoding Initiative (http://www.tei-c.org).</p>
            <p>The EEBO-TCP project was divided into two phases. The 25,368 texts created during Phase 1 of the project (2000-2009), initially available only to institutions that contributed to their creation, were released into the public domain on 1 January 2015. The approximately 40,000 texts produced during Phase 2 (2009- ), of which 34,963 had been released as of 2020, originally similarly restricted, were similarly freed from all restrictions on 1 August 2020. As of that date anyone is free to take and use these texts for any purpose (modify them, annotate them, distribute them, etc.). But we do respectfully request that due credit and attribution be given to their original source.</p>
            <p>Users should be aware of the process of creating the TCP texts, and therefore of any assumptions that can be made about the data.</p>
            <p>Text selection was based on the New Cambridge Bibliography of English Literature (NCBEL). If an author (or for an anonymous work, the title) appears in NCBEL, then their works are eligible for inclusion. Selection was intended to range over a wide variety of subject areas, to reflect the true nature of the print record of the period. In general, first editions of a works in English were prioritized, although there are a number of works in other languages, notably Latin and Welsh, included and sometimes a second or later edition of a work was chosen if there was a compelling reason to do so.</p>
            <p>Image sets were sent to external keying companies for transcription and basic encoding. Quality assurance was then carried out by editorial teams in Oxford and Michigan. 5% (or 5 pages, whichever is the greater) of each text was proofread for accuracy and those which did not meet QA standards were returned to the keyers to be redone. After proofreading, the encoding was enhanced and/or corrected and characters marked as illegible were corrected where possible up to a limit of 100 instances per text. Any remaining illegibles were encoded as &lt;gap&gt;s. Understanding these processes should make clear that, while the overall quality of TCP data is very good, some errors will remain and some readable characters will be marked as illegible. Users should bear in mind that in all likelihood such instances will never have been looked at by a TCP editor.</p>
            <p>The texts were encoded and linked to page images in accordance with level 4 of the TEI in Libraries guidelines.</p>
            <p>Copies of the texts have been issued variously as SGML (TCP schema; ASCII text with mnemonic sdata character entities); displayable XML (TCP schema; characters represented either as UTF-8 Unicode or text strings within braces); or lossless XML (TEI P5, characters represented either as UTF-8 Unicode or TEI g elements).</p>
            <p>Keying and markup guidelines are available at the <ref target="http://www.textcreationpartnership.org/docs/.">Text Creation Partnership web site</ref>.</p>
         </editorialDecl>
         <listPrefixDef>
            <prefixDef ident="tcp"
                       matchPattern="([0-9\-]+):([0-9IVX]+)"
                       replacementPattern="http://eebo.chadwyck.com/downloadtiff?vid=$1&amp;page=$2"/>
            <prefixDef ident="char"
                       matchPattern="(.+)"
                       replacementPattern="https://raw.githubusercontent.com/textcreationpartnership/Texts/master/tcpchars.xml#$1"/>
         </listPrefixDef>
      </encodingDesc>
      <profileDesc>
         <langUsage>
            <language ident="eng">eng</language>
         </langUsage>
         <textClass>
            <keywords scheme="http://authorities.loc.gov/">
               <term>Apocalyptic literature.</term>
               <term>Prophecies.</term>
            </keywords>
         </textClass>
      </profileDesc>
      <revisionDesc>
         <change>
            <date>2013-10</date>
            <label>TCP</label>Assigned for keying and markup</change>
         <change>
            <date>2013-10</date>
            <label>SPi Global</label>Keyed and coded from ProQuest page images</change>
         <change>
            <date>2013-11</date>
            <label>Judith Siefring</label>Sampled and proofread</change>
         <change>
            <date>2013-11</date>
            <label>Judith Siefring</label>Text and markup reviewed and edited</change>
         <change>
            <date>2014-03</date>
            <label>pfs</label>Batch review (QC) and XML conversion</change>
      </revisionDesc>
   </teiHeader>
   <text xml:lang="eng">
      <front>
         <div type="title_page">
            <pb facs="tcp:105773:1"/>
            <pb facs="tcp:105773:1" rendition="simple:additions"/>
            <p>OF Times and Seaſons THEIR MYSTERY.</p>
            <p>By the Lady <hi>Eleanor.</hi>
            </p>
            <q>
               <bibl>
                  <hi>DAN. 2.</hi>
               </bibl>
               <p>And Daniel anſwered and ſaid, The Name of God be praiſed; for Ages of Ages; for Wiſdom and Strength are his; for he changeth the Times and Seaſons, <hi>&amp;c.</hi>
               </p>
            </q>
            <p>Printed in the Year. 1651.</p>
         </div>
      </front>
      <body>
         <div type="text">
            <pb facs="tcp:105773:2"/>
            <pb n="3" facs="tcp:105773:2"/>
            <head>A PREFACE or APPEAL.</head>
            <p>THe <hi>Revelations Goſpel; bleſs<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ed Book</hi> of the Prophet <hi>Da<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>vids Generation</hi> cometh not (as teſtifies) by <hi>fleſh</hi> onely, this <hi>Man-childe</hi> of the <hi>Woman ſeed,</hi> but diverſly as in days of old <hi>God</hi> ſpake then; ſo now of his <hi>Sons</hi> coming after <hi>one</hi> and the <hi>ſame way,</hi> by <hi>things</hi> paſt, as though preſent, as follows of that <hi>Tyrant Herod</hi> again and his fol<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>lowers; who with an <hi>Iron Scepter,</hi> the <hi>Revolted Nations</hi> ſubdues, whoſe <hi>Rod</hi> inſtead of <hi>Kiſsing,</hi> to depoſe <hi>him,</hi> taking <hi>Counſel</hi> with one conſent.</p>
            <pb n="4" facs="tcp:105773:3"/>
            <p>Touching which <hi>Sacred Oracles,</hi> for as much as no few having taken upon them, unacquainted with ſuch <hi>Pedigrees Myſtery,</hi> untimely to gather of this <hi>Paradiſe Tree,</hi> this hidden <hi>Manna,</hi> conſiſting of <hi>Times Myſtery</hi> and <hi>Seaſons;</hi> breathed by the <hi>Father</hi> the <hi>breath of life.</hi> There<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>with <hi>Miracles</hi> and <hi>Gifts</hi> of <hi>Tongues</hi> not Equivalent.</p>
            <p>Have here conceived not amiſs concerning this <hi>Conception</hi> by the <hi>Holy Ghoſt,</hi> the <hi>Fathers</hi> proper <hi>Dar<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ling,</hi> by a <hi>touch</hi> to thee <hi>Reader:</hi> VVhich <hi>living Tree</hi> to unfold what <hi>date</hi> it <hi>bears. Off-ſpring</hi> of <hi>David</hi> arrived its <hi>Maturity</hi> or <hi>Period</hi> at<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>tained. Thoſe <hi>Olive Leaves</hi> pre<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ſcribed for healing the <hi>Nations ma<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>lady</hi> or <hi>evil,</hi> to his ſervants the <hi>Pro<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>phets</hi>
               <pb n="5" facs="tcp:105773:3"/>for whoſe cure aforehand be<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ing <hi>revealed,</hi> by him <hi>ſtiled</hi> his <hi>friends ſervants,</hi> not being of their <hi>Maſters Privy Counſel,</hi> even things ſhortly to be done, attends or waits no lon<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ger; as ſhews, for the time is at hand (<hi>Rev.</hi> 1. <hi>cap.</hi>)</p>
            <p>Notwithſtanding his then <hi>reply,</hi> it is not for you to know <hi>times</hi> and <hi>ſeaſons, precious reſerves</hi> in the <hi>Fathers</hi> own <hi>hand,</hi> or diſpoſe for after <hi>ages;</hi> which <hi>Key</hi> of <hi>David</hi> pretended to be in their <hi>pocket,</hi> a <hi>Legacy</hi> left onely to them and their <hi>aſsigns,</hi> a <hi>ſtrain</hi> or <hi>note</hi> too high for vulgar <hi>ſpirits.</hi> His <hi>eye-ſalve anointed</hi> with <hi>Balaams.</hi>
            </p>
            <p>And thus of <hi>Jew</hi> and <hi>Gentile,</hi> born under one <hi>Planet</hi> or <hi>Sign,</hi> on this wiſe ſignified, no obſcure <hi>Characters,</hi> (<hi>Rev.</hi> 12.) <hi>And there appeared a great
<pb n="6" facs="tcp:105773:4"/>ſign in Heaven, a woman clothed or a<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>rayed with the Sun, inthroned above the Moon, Crowned with twelve Stars,</hi> no other the Golden Zodiacks ſigns, aſsigned to thoſe parts, ſhe pained to be <hi>delivered:</hi> the party otherwiſe cal<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>led a <hi>priſoner.</hi> At ſuch a time appears, <hi>&amp;c.</hi> not any thing more perſpicu<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ous and clear. VVhere inlarged thus. And there appeared another ſign in Heaven, <hi>Behold a great Red Dragon, having ſeven Heads, &amp;c. And he ſtood before the Woman,</hi> even points to the ſign <hi>Virgo,</hi> by the word <hi>Virga, Arod;</hi> where <hi>Scorpio</hi> follows. The <hi>Dragons Tail</hi> imparts no leſs, the third part of Stars drawing after him, with <hi>Michaels</hi> alarm, the <hi>Arch<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>angels.</hi> The <hi>Suns</hi> appointed <hi>progreſs</hi> diſplayes about the fall <hi>September,
<pb n="7" facs="tcp:105773:4"/>&amp;c.</hi> Day and Night, when going to <hi>halfs</hi> for the <hi>hours:</hi> with the Ser<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>pents looſing his place then, by the <hi>flaming ſword</hi> expelled, wherewith proceeding <hi>ſufferings</hi> of this her <hi>ſeed,</hi> no <hi>new Goſpel</hi> but that from the beginning, as he wrote to that <hi>Lady.</hi> So of this <hi>Deified perſons</hi> deſcription, adorned with thoſe <hi>Celeſtials inno<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>cence</hi> in its colours, ſhe in travel, <hi>&amp;c.</hi> That <hi>Oſtetrix</hi> where imbrew'd, ſtood before her in his proper colours alſo with open mouth, drawn from <hi>head</hi> to <hi>tail,</hi> the <hi>Epiſcopal Antichriſtian Order</hi> (attended with his <hi>Train</hi>) ſti<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>led <hi>The old Serpent the Devil, that Father rather,</hi> as much to ſay, <hi>Anno Dom. Octobris Michaelis, Coram Pa<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>tri totius Angliae, &amp;c.</hi> Such a one ſhe appeared, <hi>perſonally</hi> to receive their
<pb n="8" facs="tcp:105773:5"/>judgement, thence even to be carri<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ed away by water <hi>cloſe priſoner</hi> to the <hi>Gatehouſe,</hi> witneſs. And the <hi>Serpent</hi> caſt out of his <hi>mouth</hi> water after the <hi>Woman,</hi> as a flood, that he might cauſe her to be carried away of the flood; wherewith he in the ſeven<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>teenth <hi>Century</hi> ſhut up in the <hi>Ark Noah.</hi> Thoſe days caſt into the <hi>account.</hi> As <hi>Item,</hi> Againſt them his waging VVar; thoſe keeping the <hi>Commandments: Idolatry</hi> for queſtioning it: Incenſed that rem<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>nant that had not bowed the <hi>knee</hi> to <hi>Baals</hi> Altar.</p>
            <p>
               <hi>All with one voice. How marvel<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>lous are thy works:</hi> VVitneſs <hi>Babes, Sucklings, Heavens, Moon</hi> and <hi>Stars,</hi> ordained to praiſe his <hi>Name,</hi> whilſt others as faln into a <hi>Lithargy,</hi> ſnoring <gap reason="missing" extent="1+ pages">
                  <desc>〈1… pages missing〉</desc>
               </gap>
            </p>
            <pb facs="tcp:105773:5" rendition="simple:additions"/>
         </div>
      </body>
   </text>
</TEI>
